# Brian Mwendwa



brianmwendwa.mu@gmail.com



+254796898480



linkedin.com/in/brian-mwendwa-25326a173



https://mwendwa.netlify.app/

## Summary

I am naturally inquisitive; I like to learn and explore new ideas. I believe in the inevitability of change and work towards adapting to change. I am a passionate software developer with experience in JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Cloud Development and Architecture. The fable of the Crow and the Pitcher is what best represents my professional journey.

## **Experience**



#### **Software Developer**

Vulnerable Children Concern Kenya

Oct 2020 - Oct 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- 1. Wrote well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices like High Cohesion - Low Coupling to reduce module complexion.
- 2. Built website layout/user interfaces by using standard ReactJS components as well as React Hooks integrating data from various back-end services and databases.
- 3. Intergrated a backend email service with nodemailer.



#### Web Developer

Pemter Group Kenya

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021 (7 months)

- 1. Collaborated with a team of developers to design the data and presentation layer of the web application's front-end with Material ui and Figma.
- 2. Used additional JavaScript libraries such as React Context API and Recoil to manage the web application's state, derive computed data from the state of the system, and make asynchronous API
- 3. Tested and updated the web application with Jest so that it can be used on all web browsers.



#### Web Developer Internship

Conceptshub

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021 (3 months)

- 1. Designed wireframes with Figma and Adobe illustrator.
- 2. Worked with the development team to develop backend and front-end applications with Express, Mongo and React JS.
- 3. Deployed web applications through Continuous Integration/Development on GitHub.
- 4. Collaborated with developers to implement new web features.



#### 🕍 Information Technology Intern

Kenya Ministry of Agriculture, Livestock, Fisheries and Cooperatives Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 (4 months)

1. Handled network routing and configuration for various departments within the Ministry.

- 2. Installed and configured computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, and scanners.
- 3. Provided technical support across the company.

#### **Education**



### Africa International University

Bachelor's degree, IT May 2018 - Dec 2021



#### KCA University

Cisco Certified Network Associate, Computer Systems Networking and **Telecommunications** 

2019 - 2020

Enterprise Networking, Security, and Automation

The student was able to proficiently:

- 1. Configure single-area OSPFv2 in both point-to-point and multiaccess networks.
- 2. Implement standard IPv4 ACLs to filter traffic and secure administrative
- 3. Configure NAT services on the edge router to provide IPv4 address scalability.
- 4. Implement protocols to manage the network.



## Starehe Boys' Centre and School

**High School Certificate** Jan 2013 - Nov 2017

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



#### Blockchain Intro - IBM

gs180234bsit@aiu.ac.ke



#### SOLOLEARN HTML FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFICATE - Sololearn

Certificate #1014-9733611



#### **Usable Security** - Coursera

3UTB6ZM8RZKV



## Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) - Cisco



- Node.js V2 IBM
- (A) JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures freeCodeCamp
- Modern JavaScript for ReactJS ES6 Udemy UC-1ad2b96d-feef-45a1-bd8c-19f98d0a967b
- **AWS Services for Solutions Architect 2021** Udemy UC-6947d87c-dca5-4d93-8dbd-1d2f959a00b1

#### **Skills**

Programming • React.js • MongoDB • JavaScript • Web Development

#### **Honors & Awards**

Certificate of Participation - Kenya Red Cross Society
Aug 2016

Was enrolled as a Youth Member of the Kenya Red Cross Society, joining others all over the world to help the sick and suffering.